我们受到攻击
We are under attack.
那儿有很多怪物
There are creatures.
我不觉得它们是人类
I don't even think they're human.
我们阻止不了它们
We can't stop them.
这座时钟坏了 他要来了
The clock is broken. He's coming.
你听到我的话了吗
Did you hear what I said?
听我说 有个人要来凡尔赛
Listen to me. There is a man coming to Versailles.
他守护了我的一生 今晚他也不会抛弃我
He has watched over me my whole life and he will not desert me tonight.
你在说什么 什么人
What are you talking about? What man?
除你之外 我唯一爱过的人
The only man, save you, I have ever loved.
不要这样 没有时间了
No, don't look like that. There's no time.
你有你的职责
You have your duties.
我只是一个妃子 去找你的王后吧
I am your mistress. Go to your queen.
你在吗 你能听见我吗
Are you there? Can you hear me?
我现在需要你 你答应过的
I need you now, you promised.
壁炉上的钟已经坏了
The clock on the mantel is broken.
时间到了
It is time.
博士 博士
Doctor! Doctor!
神秘博士
壁炉女孩
编剧 史蒂文·莫法特
未来 3000 年后
这是宇宙飞船 太棒了
It's a spaceship. Brilliant!
第一次出来就遇到了宇宙飞船
I got a spaceship on my first go.
看上去已经被遗弃了 船上有人吗
ROSE: Looks kind of abandoned. Anyone on board?
没有 什么都没有
Nah, nothing here.
噢 什么危险都没有
Well, nothing dangerous.
我是说 不是那种危险
Well, not that dangerous.
你知道吗 我要快速扫瞄一下
You know what? I'll just have a quick scan.
以防有任何危险
In case there's anything dangerous.
那么 现在是什么时间 我们走了多远
So, what's the date? How far have we gone?
相对你们大约3000年后的未来
About 3,000 years into your future,
信不信由你
give or take.
51世纪
51st century.
达格玛星群 你离家很远了 米奇
The Dagmar Cluster, you're a long way from home, Mickey!
两个半星系
Two and a half galaxies.
米奇·史密斯 跟宇宙打个招呼吧
Mickey Smith, meet the universe.
喜欢吗
See anything you like?
太真实了
It's so realistic!
天呐 难道有牛仔来过这儿
Dear me, had some cowboys in here.
一大堆东西需要修理
Been a ton of repair work going on.
这可奇怪了 瞧啊
Now that's odd, look at that.
所有的拖拽引擎都在工作
All the warp engines are going.
还是全速推进
Full capacity.
这艘船上流通的能量
There's enough power running through this ship
足够把宇宙轰出个洞了
to punch a hole in the universe
而飞船却动也不动
and we're not moving.
那么 所有的能量都哪儿去了
So where's all that power going?
船员们都去哪儿了
Where'd all the crew go?
问得好 船上没有生命迹象
Good question. No life readings on board.
我们在外太空
Well, we're in deep space.
他们不会只是出去吸口烟吧
They didn't just nip out for a quick fag.
不是 我已经检查了所有的吸烟室
No, I've checked all the smoking pods.
你闻到了吗
You smell that?
闻到了 谁在做饭
Yeah. Someone's cooking.
肯定是周末烧烤
Sunday roast, definitely.
现在
Now,
这可是一般飞船上不会有的东西
there's something you don't see in your average spaceship.
18世纪
18th century.
法式的
French.
不错的壁炉架
Nice mantel.
不是全息图
Not a hologram.
甚至不是复制品
Not even a reproduction.
这是一个千真万确的18世纪的法国壁炉
This actually is an 18th-century French fireplace.
双向通道 对面是另一个房间
Double-sided. There's another room through there.
不可能 这里是船的最外层 看呐
It can't be. That's the outer hull of the ship. Look.
你好
Hello.
Hello?
你叫什么名字
What's your name?
瑞娜特
Reinette.
瑞娜特 多可爱的名字
Reinette. That's a lovely name.
能告诉我你现在在哪里吗 瑞娜特
Can you tell me where you are at the moment, Reinette?
在我的卧室
In my bedroom.
你的卧室在哪 你家在哪 瑞娜特
And where's your bedroom? Where do you live, Reinette?
当然是巴黎
Paris of course.
巴黎 好的
Paris. Right.
先生 你在我的壁炉里干什么
Monsieur, what are you doing in my fireplace?
噢 只是一个常规的…
Oh, it's just a routine…
壁炉检查
fire check.
你能告诉我现在是哪一年吗
Can you tell me what year it is?
当然可以 1727年
Of course I can. 1727.
很好 不错 我最喜欢的年份之一
Right, lovely, one of my favourites.
虽然八月会很糟糕 好好待在家里
August is rubbish, though. Stay indoors.
好了 现在就这样吧 谢谢你的帮助
Okay, that's all for now. Thanks for your help.
希望你喜欢壁炉中的火焰 晚安
Hope you enjoy the rest of the fire. Night-night.
晚安 先生
Good night, monsieur.
你说这是51世纪
You said this was the 51st century.
我还说这艘飞船产生的能量
I also said this ship was generating enough power
足够把宇宙轰出洞口
to punch a hole in the universe.
我认为这就是我们要找的洞口了
I think we just found the hole.
一定是一个临时性时空超链接
Must be a spatio-temporal hyperlink.
什么东西
What's that?
不知道 瞎起的名字
No idea, just made it up.
因为不想叫它"魔法门"
Didn't want to say "magic door".
那么 在你这扇"魔法门"
And on the other side of the "magic door"
另一侧是1727年的法国
她是在说法语
Well, she was speaking French.
语法年代也契合
Right period French, too.
她明明在说英语 我亲耳听到的
She was speaking English, I heard her.
那是因为塔迪斯帮你翻译了
That's the Tardis, translates for you.
连法语都行
Even French?
没错
Yeah.
找到你了
Got you.
博士
Doctor!
没关系 不用尖叫
It's okay. Don't scream.
是我 你的壁炉工 你看
It's me. It's the fireplace man, look.
我们才说过话 就在刚才
We were talking. just a moment ago.
我在你的壁炉里面
I was in your fireplace.
先生 那是几个星期之前了
Monsieur, that was weeks ago.
已经一个多月了
That was months.
真的吗
Really?
一定是连接不稳定
Must be a loose connection.
得找个人修一下
Need to get a man in.
你是谁
Who are you?
你在这里做什么
What are you doing here?
好吧 这还真吓人
Okay. That's scary.
你被一个破钟给吓坏了
You're scared of a broken clock?
一点点 是啊 是有那么一点点
Just a bit scared, yeah. just a little tiny bit.
因为 要知道 如果这个钟坏了
'Cause, you see, if this clock's broken,
而它是这房间里唯一的钟
and it's the only clock in the room,
那么是什么在响
then what's that?
因为 你知道 那绝不是一个时钟
'Cause, you see, that's not a clock.
从共振频率可以知道 太大了
You can tell by the resonance. Too big.
有一米八 我估计
Six feet, I'd say.
有一个人那么大
Size of a man.
是什么
What is it?
现在 让我们来想想
Now let's think.
如果你会发出滴答声 又想躲在别人的卧室里
If you were a thing that ticked and you were hiding in someone's bedroom,
你的第一要务就是 把钟弄坏
first thing you do, break the clock.
没有人会注意一个钟的滴答声 但两个呢
No one notices the sound of one clock ticking, but two?
你可能开始怀疑你是不是独自一人
You might start to wonder if you're really alone.
待在床上 坐在正中间
Stay on the bed. Right in the middle.
手脚不要越过床边
Don't put your hands or feet over the edge.
瑞娜特
Reinette,
不要回头看
don't look round.
你待在原地别动
You stay exactly where you are.
保持静止 让我看看
Hold still, let me look.
你在扫瞄她的大脑
You've been scanning her brain!
你跨越了两个星系和几千年时间
You've crossed two galaxies and thousands of years
就为了扫瞄一个孩子的大脑
just to scan a child's brain?
这个小女孩的记忆里能有什么东西
What could there be in a little girl's mind
值得你把宇宙炸出个洞口呢
worth blowing a hole in the universe?
我不明白
I don't understand.
它想要我
It wants me?
你想要我
You want me?
目前不是 你还不完整
Not yet. You are incomplete.
不完整 什么叫还不完整
Incomplete? What does that mean, incomplete?
你可以回答她 也可以回答我
You can answer her, you can answer me.
不完整是什么意思
What do you mean, incomplete?
先生小心
Monsieur, be careful!
只是个噩梦 瑞娜特 不用担心
It's just a nightmare, Reinette. Don't worry about it.
每个人都会做噩梦
Everyone has nightmares.
甚至连床底下的怪物都有噩梦
Even monsters from under the bed have nightmares.
有没有 你这怪物
Don't you, Monster?
怪物的噩梦是什么
What do monsters have nightmares about?
是我
Me. Ha!
博士
Doctor!
太棒了 冷冻枪
Excellent. Ice gun.
是灭火器
Fire extinguisher.
那东西是从哪儿来的
Where did that thing come from?
这里
Here.
那它为什么穿成这样
MICKEY: So why is it dressed like that?
为了去法国实地考察
Field trip to France.
需要一点基本的伪装术
Some kind of basic camouflage protocol.
针线活不错嘛 这脸可不敢恭维
Nice needlework. Shame about the face.
噢 你真是太美了
Oh, you are beautiful!
真的 你简直
No, really, you are.
太华丽了 瞧瞧这个
You're gorgeous. Look at that!
太空时代的时钟 我喜欢 我都激动了
Space age clockwork. I love it. I've got chills!
听着 说真的
Listen, seriously,
我是发自内心的 不信数数 两颗心
I mean this from the heart, and by the way, count those,
那简直是犯罪 是恶意破坏
it would be a crime, it would be an act of vandalism,
我是说拆了你
to disassemble you.
但是那样也不能阻止我
But that won't stop me.
短距离瞬时传送
Short-range teleport.
走不远 可能还在船上
Can't have got far. Could still be on board.
它是什么东西
What is it?
不要去找它
Don't go looking for it.
你去哪里
Where are you going?
一会儿就回来
Back in a sec.
他叫我们别去找
He said not to look for it.
没错 他是这么说的
Yeah, he did.
现在你总算开窍了
Now you're getting it.
瑞娜特
Reinette?
只是来检查下你的情况
just checking you're okay.
噢 你好
Oh. Hello!
我只是在找瑞娜特
I was just looking for Reinette.
这里还是她的房间吧
This is still her room, isn't it?
我离开了一会儿
I've been away,
不确定是多久
not sure how long.
瑞娜特 准备走了
WOMAN: Reinette? We're ready to go!
到马车上去 妈妈 我到那与你们会合
Go to the carriage, Mother, I will join you there.
我觉得 拥有一个幻想中的朋友
It is customary, I think, to have an imaginary friend
只有在儿童时期才正常吧
only during one's childhood.
真该祝贺你的存在能持续到今天
You are to be congratulated on your persistence.
瑞娜特
Reinette.
哇…
Well…
天哪 你长大了
Goodness, how you've grown.
而你好像一天都没变老
And you do not appear to have aged a single day.
这简直太无礼了
That is tremendously impolite of you.
是啊 对不起 呃
Right, yes, sorry. Um…
听着 很高兴能够赶上你们
Listen, lovely to catch up
但我最好还是先告辞了
but better be off, eh?
不希望你妈妈发现你
Don't want your mother finding you up here
和一个陌生男子在一起 对吧
with a strange man, do we?
陌生人
Strange?
你怎么会是我的陌生人
How could you be a stranger to me?
我从七岁起就认识你了
I have known you since I was seven years old.
我猜也是
Yeah, I suppose you have.
我是抄近路来的
I came the quick route.
你就这么活生生的站在我面前
You seem to be flesh and blood at any rate,
但是这一点也不合理
but this is absurd.
理智告诉我你不可能是真的
Reason tells me you cannot be real.
噢 你不会喜欢听从理智的
Oh, you never want to listen to reason.
小姐 你母亲已经等得不耐烦了
MAN: Mademoiselle? Your mother grows impatient.
就一会儿
A moment!
那么多话要说
So many questions.
时间却那么少
So little time.
帕瓦松小姐
Mademoiselle Poisson!
帕瓦松
Poisson!
瑞娜特·帕瓦松
Reinette Poisson.
不是吧
No!
不不不 不可能
No, no, no, no! No way!
瑞娜特·帕瓦松
Reinette Poisson.
后来的德·蒂奥勒夫人
Later Madame d'Étiolles.
再后来的路易十五的妃子
Later still, mistress of Louis XV,
法兰西的无冕女王
uncrowned Queen of France!
女演员 艺术家 音乐家
Actress, artist, musician,
舞蹈家 交际花
dancer, courtesan.
出色的园艺家
Fantastic gardener.
你到底是谁
Who the hell are you?
我是博士
I'm the Doctor.
而且我刚刚吻了蓬帕杜尔女士
And I just snogged Madame de Pompadour.
洛斯
Rose?
米奇 每次 每次都这样
Mickey! Every time. Every time!
这是首要规则 不要乱逛
It's rule one. Don't wander off.
我真的说过 首要规则
I tell them, I do. Rule one.
根本不知道这船上会出现什么
There could be anything on this ship!
你在盯着我看
Are you looking at me?
快来 看这个
Look! Look at this!
里面有只眼睛
That's an eye in there.
那是只真正的眼睛
That's a real eye.
那是什么
What is that?
中间那个是什么 像是接上了电线
What's that in the middle there? Looks like it's wired in.
那是一颗心脏 米奇
It's a heart, Mickey.
人的心脏
It's a human heart.
洛斯
Rose?
能不能别跟着我
Will you stop following me?
我又不是你妈
I'm not your mother.
你就是从这儿来的吧 小马
So this is where you came from, eh, horsey?
噢 凯瑟琳你太坏了
Oh, Katherine, you are too wicked.
说到坏
Oh, speaking of wicked,
我听说德沙德鲁夫人病入膏肓了
I hear Madame de Chéteauroux is ill and close to death.
是 我都震惊了
Yes, I am devastated.
噢 确实
Oh, indeed.
我经常暗自难过
I, myself, am frequently inconsolable.
国王将需要一名新妃子
KATHERINE: The King will therefore be requiring a new mistress.
当然 你爱国王
You love the King, of course.
他是国王 我会全心全意地爱他
He is the King and I love him with all my heart.
我非常期盼着见到他
And I look forward to meeting him.
亲爱的 有什么不对的吗
Is something wrong, my dear?
没有 没事
Not wrong, no.
巴黎的每个女人都知道你的野心
KATHERINE: Every woman in Paris knows your ambitions.
巴黎的每个女人也有同样的野心
REINETTE: Every woman in Paris shares them.
当然 你知道国王准备参加紫杉树舞会
You know, of course, that the King is to attend the Yew Tree Ball…
也许不是一颗真的心脏呢
Maybe it wasn't a real heart.
当然是颗真的心脏
of course it was a real heart.
这对你来说很平常吗
Is this, like, normal for you?
这些就是你的日常生活吗
Is this an average day?
米奇 和博士一起旅行
Life with the Doctor, Mickey,
从来都没有正常的日子
no more average days.
又是法国 从这儿能看到法国
It's France again. We can see France.
我觉得我们正在透过一面镜子观察
I think we're looking through a mirror.
啊呀 看这个人
Blimey, look at this guy!
他以为自己是谁
Who does he think he is?
法国国王
King of France.
噢 有麻烦了 你上哪儿去了
Oh, here's trouble. What you been up to?
噢 我到处逛了逛
Oh, this and that.
成为一个未来的法国贵族幻想的朋友
Became the imaginary friend of a future French aristocrat,
然后和一个钟表人打了一架
picked a fight with a clockwork man.
噢 我还遇到一匹马
Oh, and I met a horse.
一匹马在宇宙飞船上干嘛
What's a horse doing on a spaceship?
米奇 革命前的法国出现在宇宙飞船上干嘛
Mickey, what's pre-revolutionary France doing on a spaceship?
有点观察力吧
Get a little perspective.
看到这些没有
See these?
它们遍布整个地方 每个甲板
They're all over the place, on every deck.
通往历史的大门
Gateways to history.
但不是随便什么人的历史
But not just any old history.
是她的历史
Hers.
时间之窗
Time window.
特意安排地
Deliberately arranged
贯穿了一个特定的女人的一生
along the life of one particular woman.
一艘来自51世纪的宇宙飞船
A spaceship from the 51 st century
暗中偷窥一个18世纪的女人
stalking a woman from the 18th.
为什么
Why?
她是谁
Who is she?
让娜-安托瓦妮特·帕瓦松
Jean-Antoinette Poisson.
她的朋友叫她瑞娜特
Known to her friends as Reinette.
历史上最博学多识的女人之一
One of the most accomplished women who ever lived.
那么 她已经计划好成为王后了
So has she got plans for being the queen, then?
不 他已经有了王后了
No, he's already got a queen.
她计划做他的妃子
She's got plans on being his mistress.
噢 我知道了
Oh, I get it.
《情伴我心》
Camilla!
我认为这就是他们见面的那个晚上
I think this is the night they met.
紫杉树舞会之夜
The night of the Yew Tree Ball.
不久之后
In no time flat,
她会成功地正式确立为皇妃
she'll get herself established as his official mistress
在宫中占有一席之地 甚至拥有了自己的头衔
with her own rooms at the palace, even her own title.
蓬帕杜尔夫人
Madame de Pompadour.
王后一定很喜欢她
The Queen must have loved her.
噢 确实 他们相处的很好
No, she did. They got on very well.
国王的妻子和国王的女朋友
The King's wife and the King's girlfriend?
法国 是个不一样的世界
France. It's a different planet.
你在这里站了多久了
How long have you been standing there?
快现身
Show yourself!
你好 瑞娜特 时间过得真快
Hello, Reinette, hasn't time flown!
壁炉工
Fireplace man!
它在做什么
What's it doing?
正在重启 把冰融化
Switching back on. Melting the ice.
然后呢
And then what?
然后杀死房间里的每一个人
Then it kills everyone in the room.
挺执着的嘛 有没有
Focuses the mind, doesn't it?
你是谁 表明你的身份
Who are you? Identify yourself.
命令它回答我的问题
Order it to answer me.
为什么它会听我的
Why should it listen to me?
我不知道 但是你小时候它就听你的
I don't know, but it did when you were a child.
让我们试试看现在还管不管用
Let's see if you've still got it.
回答他的问题
Answer his question.
如实回答他问你的任何问题
Answer any and all questions put to you.
我是维修机器人七号
I am Repair Droid 7.
那么这艘船发生什么事了
And what happened to the ship, then?
飞船损坏十分严重
There was a lot of damage.
离子风暴 造成82%的系统失灵
Ion storm. 82% systems failure.
那艘船已经一年多没动过了
That ship hasn't moved in over a year.
什么耽搁你们这么久
What's taken you so long?
我们缺少零件
We did not have the parts.
总是归结到这个原因 不是吗 零件
Always comes down to that, doesn't it? The parts.
船员们怎么了 他们在哪里
What's happened to the crew? Where are they?
我们缺少零件
We did not have the parts.
你们船上应该至少有50人 他们去哪里了
There should've been over 50 people on your ship. Where did they go?
我们缺少零件
We did not have the parts.
50个人不可能就这样消失 他们…
Fifty people don't just disappear, where…
噢
Oh.
你们缺少零件 所以你们使用了船员
You didn't have the parts so you used the crew.
船员
The crew?
我们发现一个有眼睛的照相机
We found a camera with an eye in it.
还有一颗心脏接在机器中
And there was a heart wired into machinery.
它只是在按照程序办事
It's just doing what it was programmed to.
不惜一切修理船体 用尽一切能找到的东西
Repairing the ship any way it can with whatever it can find.
又没人说过不能使用船员
No one told it the crew weren't on the menu.
你说在甲板上闻到什么
What did you say the flight deck smelled of?
有人在做饭
Someone cooking.
烤熟的人肉
Flesh plus heat.
烧烤
Barbecue.
但是你在这里做什么
But what are you doing here?
你开启了时间窗口 那得耗费巨大的能量
You've opened up time windows, that takes colossal energy.
为什么来这里 你应该去你的修理间
Why come here? You could've gone to your repair yard.
然而你却来到18世纪的法国 为什么
Instead you come to 18th-century France? Why?
还缺少最后一个零件
One more part is required.
那你为什么还没取走
Then why haven't you taken it?
她还不完整
She is incomplete.
什么 那就是你的计划
What? So that's the plan, then?
不停地打开更多时间窗口
just keep opening up more and more time windows,
扫瞄她的大脑 检查她是否完整了
scanning her brain, checking to see if she's done yet?
为什么是她
Why her?
如果你可以从历史中任意挑选
You've got all of history to choose from,
为什么特地要选她
why specifically her?
我们是相同的
We are the same.
我们不同 我们没有任何理由相同
We're not the same. We are in no sense the same!
我们是相同的
We are the same.
给我出去
Get out of here.
立即滚出去
Get out of here this instant.
瑞娜特 不
Reinette, no.
它回到飞船上去了 洛斯
It's back on the ship! Rose,
带上米奇和亚瑟去跟踪它
take Mickey and Arthur, get after it, follow it.
不要靠近它 只需要观察它做什么
Don't approach it, just watch what it does.
亚瑟
Arthur?
我给那匹马起的名字
Good name for a horse.
你该不会是要收留那匹马吧
No, you're not keeping the horse.
你都允许你收留米奇了
I let you keep Mickey. Now go, go, go!
现在 走走走
Now go, go, go!
瑞娜特 你现在必须相信我
Reinette, You're going to have to trust me.
我需要知道它们想要什么
I need to find out what they're looking for.
我只有一个办法能做到
There's only one way I can do that.
一点都不会疼的
Won't hurt a bit.
壁炉工
Fireplace man.
你进入了我的头脑
You are inside my mind.
噢 亲爱的瑞娜特
Oh, clear, Reinette.
你的回忆真是一言难尽啊
You've had some cowboys in here.
那么 这个博士哟
So, that Doctor, eh?
你想说什么
What are you talking about?
蓬帕杜尔夫人 莎拉·简·史密斯…
Well! Madame de Pompadour, Sarah Jane Smith.
克丽尔帕特拉
Cleopatra…
克丽尔帕特拉 他只提到过一次
Cleopatra! He mentioned her once!
是的 但他叫她克丽儿
Yeah, but he called her Cleo.
米奇
Mickey!
你在我的记忆里
You are in my memories.
你在记忆中穿行
You walk among them.
如果有什么不想让我看到
If there's anything you don't want me to see,
你就想像一扇门然后关上
just imagine a door and close it.
我不会偷看的
I won't look.
事实上 那儿就有一扇门
Oh, actually, there's a door just there,
你可能想关掉 哇哦
you might want to close…Oh.
事实上 有好几个呢
Actually, several.
在另一个鲜活的灵魂的记忆里穿行
To walk among the memories of another living soul.
你经常这么做吗
Do you ever get used to this?
我没有这样的习惯
I don't make a habit of it.
你怎么忍得住
How can you resist?
你几岁了
What age are you?
这个问题真没礼貌
So impertinent a question
现在讨论有点早吧
so early in the conversation.
多么有希望
How promising.
不是我的问题 它们的问题
Not my question. Theirs.
你23岁 由于某些原因 你还不够成熟
You're 23. And for some reason that means you're not old enough.
抱歉 可能唤醒了一些陈旧的记忆 副作用
Sorry. You might find old memories reawakening. Side effect.
噢 多么孤独的童年
Oh, such a lonely childhood.
会过去的 坚持一下
It'll pass. Stay with me.
噢 博士
Oh, Doctor.
好孤单 非常非常孤独
So lonely. So very, very alone.
你说什么 孤单
What do you mean, alone?
你这一生从未怎么孤单啊
You've never been alone in your life.
你什么时候开始叫我博士了
When did you start calling me Doctor?
多么孤单的小男孩
Such a lonely little boy.
那时孤单 现在更孤单
Lonely then and lonelier now.
你怎么能忍受
How can you bear it?
你怎么做到的
How did you do that?
一扇门一旦被打开了
A door once opened
也许能够双向通行呢
may be stepped through in either direction.
噢 博士
Oh, Doctor.
我孤单的博士
My lonely Doctor.
和我跳舞
Dance with me.
我不能
I can't.
和我跳舞
Dance with me.
这是你和国王跳舞的夜晚
This is the night you dance with the King.
那我首先要让他妒忌一下
Then first I shall make him jealous.
我不能
I can't.
博士
Doctor.
神秘博士
Doctor who?
这不仅仅是个秘密 对吧
It's more than just a secret, isn't it?
你看到了什么
What did you see?
那个时间总会到来的 时间领主
That there comes a time, Time Lord,
每个孤单的小男孩
when every lonely little boy
总有一天要学会如何跳舞
must learn how to dance.
这是什么 发生什么了
What is this? What's going on?
博士
Doctor?
洛斯
Rose?
它们要把我们切碎 就像那些船员
They're going to chop us up. just like the crew!
它们要把我们切开
They're going to chop us up and
然后用在它们那混帐宇宙飞船上
stick us all over their stupid spaceship.
博士在哪里
And where's the Doctor?
你的宝贝博士在哪儿
Where's your precious Doctor now?
他自己逍遥快活去了 肯定是的
He's been gone for ﬂipping hours, that's where he is!
你可以兼容
You are compatible.
这个嘛 你…
Well, you...
你可能需要好好考虑一下
you might want to think about that.
你真的需要 因为我和米奇
You really, really might because me and Mickey,
我们不是单独来的 不是
we didn't come here alone, no, no.
相信我 你不会想
And trust me, you wouldn't want to
和我们的代驾司机惹上事的
mess with our designated driver.
听说过戴立克没有
Ever heard of the Daleks?
记得他们吗
Remember them?
他们给我的朋友起了个名字
They had a name for our friend.
有关于他以及这个名字的传说
They had myths about him and a name.
他们称他为…
They called him the…
♪ I could have danced all night ♪
他们称他为…
They called him…
♪ And still have begged for more! ♪
♪ I could have spread my wings, And…♪
你们去过法国没有
Have you met the French?
我的天哪
My God,
他们太会开派对了
they know how to party!
看看这只猫抓到了什么
Oh, look at what the cat dragged in.
暴风雨即将来临
The Oncoming Storm.
噢 你说话就像你妈妈
You sound just like your mother.
你刚刚在哪里 你去哪儿了
What have you been doing? Where have you been?
这个嘛
Well
其中一件事是 好像
Well, among other things, I think
我刚刚提前了几个世纪发明了香蕉鸡尾酒
I just invented the banana daiquiri a couple of centuries early.
你知道吗 他们之前从没见过香蕉
Do you know, they'd never even seen a banana before?
参加聚会时一定要带上香蕉 洛斯
Always take a banana to a party, Rose.
香蕉最好了
Bananas are good!
噢 太棒了
Oh, brilliant.
是你啊
It's you!
你是我的最爱 你就是
You're my favourite, you are.
你是最优秀的一个 知道为什么吗
You are the best. Do you know why?
因为你是那么蠢
'Cause you're so thick.
你是最蠢最傻最笨的傻瓜先生
You're Mr Thick Thick Thicketty Thick-face
来自傻瓜国的傻瓜镇
from Thick-town, Thickania.
你老爸也是
And so is your dad.
你知道它们想从瑞娜特的大脑里找什么吗
Do you know what they were scanning Reinette's brain for?
她的里程表
Her milometer.
它们想知道她几岁了
They want to know how old she is.
知道为什么吗
Know why?
因为这艘船正好37岁
Cause this ship is 37 years old.
它们认为瑞娜特到37岁
And they think when Reinette is 37,
那时她就"完整"了
when she's complete,
然后她的大脑就兼容了
then her brain will be compatible.
那就是你们缺少的东西 对吧
'Cause that's what you're missing, isn't it, hmm?
你的电脑环绕着这个命令
Command circuit, your computer.
你的飞船需要一个大脑
Your ship needs a brain.
出于某些原因 天知道是啥原因
And for some reason, God knows what,
只有蓬帕杜尔夫人的大脑才行
only the brain of Madame de Pompadour will do.
这个大脑是兼容的
The brain is compatible.
兼容
Compatible?
如果你相信那个的话
If you believe that,
你大概也会相信这是一杯红酒
you probably believe this is a glass of wine.
多重级别抗油剂
Multi-grade anti-oil.
如果它动了 然而不可能
If it moves, it doesn't.
好了 你们两个也躺够了
Right, you two, that's enough lying about.
是时候把飞船的其余部分关闭了
Time we got the rest of the ship turned off.
那些东西安全吗
Those things safe?
是的 很安全
Yep, safe.
安全而且愚蠢 正是我喜欢的样子
Safe and thick. The way I like them.
好了 所有的时间窗口都是从这里控制的
Okay, all the time windows are controlled from here.
要把它们全都关闭
Need to close them all down.
宙斯插头 我的宙斯插头在哪
Zeus plugs. Where are my Zeus plugs?
一分钟前我还拿它们当响板用呢
Had them a minute ago. I was using them as castanets.
它们为什么不直接打开
Why didn't they just open a time window
通往她37岁时的时间窗口
to when she was 37?
从这些电路的损坏程度来看
Amount of damage to these circuits,
能撞上正确的世纪算不错的了
they did well to hit the right century.
它们只能不停的试错
Trial and error after that.
时间窗口没有关闭
The windows aren't closing.
它们为什么关不掉
Why won't they close?
什么响声
What's that?
我不知道
I don't know.
收到信息
Incoming message?
谁发来的
From who?
外勤报告
Report from the field.
肯定还有一个在外面和瑞娜特在一起
One of them must still be out there with Reinette.
这就是为什么我不能关闭窗口
That's why I can't close the windows.
它重设了权限
here's an override.
还有点小聪明
That was a bit clever.
是的
Right.
与此相关的很多事情都不妙了
Many things about this are not good.
你们的小伙伴发来信息了
Message from one of your little friends?
有什么有趣的事吗
Anything interesting?
她已完整 程序启动
She is complete. It begins.
发生了什么事
What's happening?
它们其中一个找到了正确的时间窗口
One of them must have found the right time window.
现在是全军出动的时候了
It's time to send in the troops.
这次 它们要把她的头带回来
And this time they're bringing back her head.
蓬帕杜尔夫人
ROSE: Madame de Pompadour.
请不要尖叫或者惊慌 我们时间不多了
Please don't scream or anything, we haven't got a lot of time.
我来提醒你 它们会在五年后回到这里
We've come to warn you that they'll be here in five years.
五年
Five years?
你37岁生日之后的某时刻
Sometime after your 37th birthday.
我没法给你准确的时间 日期有点随机
I, um, I can't give you an exact date, it's a bit random.
但是它们会来的
But they're coming.
事情还是会发生的
It's gonna happen.
在某种程度上…
In a way,
对我们来说 已经发生过了
In a way, for us, it's already happening.
抱歉 这很难解释
I'm sorry, it's hard to explain.
还是博士比较在行
The Doctor does this better.
那就请说准确点 我会仔细听的
Then be exact and I will be attentive.
没时间了
There isn't time.
还有5年时间
There are five years.
那是对你而言 我连5分钟都没有了
For you. I haven't got five minutes.
那就长话短说
Then also be concise.
呃…
Urn…
有艘…船
There's a vessel.
飞船 一种天上飞的船
A ship. A sort of sky ship.
上面到处都是…
And it's full of…
你
Well, you.
你人生的不同时刻
Different bits of your life
在不同的房间里面乱串
in different rooms. All jumbled up.
我告诉过你挺复杂的 抱歉
I told you it was complicated, sorry.
在你的世界里有艘飞船
There is a vessel in your world
在那里我的人生被挤到一起
where the days of my life are pressed together
就像一本书的不同章节
like the chapters of a book
这样 他就能任意从一章翻到另一章
so that he may step from one to the other
而年龄不变
without increase of age
而我 一个疲倦的旅行者
while I, weary traveller,
必须一步一步地走过来
must always take the slower path.
博士对你的看法是对的
He was right about you.
所以5年之内这些生物一定会回来
So in five years these creatures will return.
我能做些什么呢
What can be done?
博士说和它们保持谈话
The Doctor says keep them talking.
它们的程序好像
They're kind of
设定好的必须要回答你
programmed to respond to you now.
你无法阻止它们
You won't be able to stop them,
但是能够拖延住它们
but you might be able to delay them a bit.
直到
Until?
直到博士赶到那里
Until the Doctor can get there.
那么说他会来
He's coming, then?
他向你保证
He promises.
但是他不能亲自过来保证吗
But he cannot make his promises in person?
你需要他的时候他就会出现
He'll be there when you need him.
只能这样进行下去
That's the way it's got to be.
这就是他一直以来的风格
It's the way it's always been.
怪物和博士
The monsters and the Doctor.
似乎两者总是同时存在 缺一不可
It seems you cannot have one without the other.
深有同感
Tell me about it.
问题是
The thing is,
你本不该遭遇它们中的任何一个
you weren't supposed to have either.
这些怪物在扰乱历史
Those creatures are messing with history.
这一切都不应该发生在你身上的
None of this was ever supposed to happen to you.
不应该发生 什么意思
Supposed to happen? What does that mean?
已经发生了 孩子
It happened, child.
我已经别无选择
And I would not have it any other way.
一个人可能为了一个天使
One may tolerate a world of demons
而容忍恶魔的存在
for the sake of an angel.
洛斯
Rose?
Rose!
洛斯
她37岁时的时间窗口
The time window where she's 37.
我们找到了 就在我们眼皮底下
We've found it, right under our noses.
不 你不能进去 博士会气死的
No, you can't go in there. The Doctor will go mad.
这就是他的世界
So this is his world.
那是什么声音
What was that?
是时间窗口 博士修复了音频连接
The time window. The Doctor fixed an audio link.
那些尖叫声
Those screams.
那就是我的未来吗
Is that my future?
是的 对不起
Yeah, I'm sorry.
看来我必须放慢步伐了
Then I must take the slower path.
你在吗 你能听到我吗
Are you there? Can you hear me?
我现在需要你 你保证过的
I need you now. You promised.
壁炉上的时钟坏了
The clock on the mantel is broken.
那是我的声音 是时侯了
That's my voice. It is time!
洛斯 快 我们要走了
Rose, come on, we've got to go.
出问题了
There's a problem.
给我点时间
Give me a moment.
你还好吗
You okay?
不好
No.
我很害怕
I'm very afraid.
但是你我都知道 是吧 洛斯
But you and I both know, don't we, Rose?
博士值得我们等待
The Doctor is worth the monsters.
博士 博士
Doctor! Doctor!
博士
Doctor!
我们必须走了
We must go!
没有人会来帮我们的
No one is coming to help us.
你已经完整了 你必须来
You are complete. You will come.
你们找到了
You found it, then?
它们知道我要来 把时间窗口封住了
They knew I was coming, they've blocked it off.
我们要去哪儿
Where are we going?
瞬时传送距离有限
The teleport has limited range.
我们必须接近时间入口
We must have proximity to the time portal.
你的话毫无意义
Your words mean nothing.
你什么都不是
You are nothing.
我不明白 它们怎么进去那里的
I don't get it. How come they got in there?
它们瞬时传送过去的
They teleported. You saw them.
只要飞船和舞厅还有连接
As long as the ship and the ballroom are linked,
它们的短程瞬时传送就能做到这小把戏
their short-range teleports will do the trick.
我们用塔迪斯吧
We'll go in the Tardis.
不能用塔迪斯 我们已经卷进事件之中了
We can't use the Tardis. We're part of events now.
难道我们不能冲过去
Can't we just smash through?
这边是超空间簇 那边是厚玻璃板
Hyperplex this side, plate glass the other.
得有一辆卡车才行
We'd need a truck.
我们没有卡车
We don't have a truck.
我知道我们没有卡车
I know we don't have a truck !
那我们试试什么
We've got to try something!
不行 玻璃一碎 时间窗口也没了
No. Smash the glass, smash the time windows.
就没有回来的路了
There'd be no way back.
大家能不能冷静下来
Could everyone just calm down!
请冷静
Please!
这骚乱 这沮丧的吵闹
Such a commotion. Such distressing noise.
容我提醒一下
Kindly remember that
这里是凡尔赛宫
this is Versailles.
这是皇室宫廷 我们是法国人
This is the Royal Court and we are French.
我决定了
I have made a decision.
我的决定是"不"
And my decision is no.
我今天不会跟你走的
I shall not be going with you today.
我见过你们的世界
I have seen your world
我不想再次涉足那里
and I have no desire to set foot there again.
我们不需要你的足
We do not require your feet.
你以为我怕你
You think I fear you,
但我就算现在也不怕你
but I do not fear you even now.
你只不过是我小时候的噩梦
You are merely the nightmare of my childhood,
床底下的怪物
the monster from under my bed.
如果我的噩梦能回来折磨我
And if my nightmare can return to plague me,
请相信 你的噩梦也会回来
then rest assured, so will yours.
蓬帕杜尔夫人
Madame de Pompadour.
你看起来越来越年轻了
You look younger every day.
到底是怎么回事
What the hell is going on?
噢 这是我的爱人 法国国王
Oh. This is my lover, the King of France.
是吗
Yeah?
我还是时间领主呢
Well, I'm the Lord of Time.
我这就来修好你的时钟
And I'm here to fix the clock.
死心吧 都结束了
Forget it. It's over.
我们双方都结束了
For you and for me.
说到七年的厄运
Talk about seven years' bad luck.
尝尝三千年如何
Try 3,000.
怎么回事
What happened?
时间窗口去哪儿了
Where did the time window go?
他要怎么回来
How's he gonna get back?
与飞船的连接断开了 回不去了
The link with the ship is broken. No way back.
你没有零件
You don't have the parts.
你那时钟心脏还能跳多久
How many ticks left in that clockwork heart, huh?
一天 一小时
A day? An hour?
结束了 接受事实吧
It's over. Accept that.
我可不会给你上发条
I'm not winding you up.
没事吧
Are you all right?
它们怎么了
What's happened to them?
它们停住了
They've stopped.
它们现在没有目标了
They have no purpose now.
没有他我们开不了塔迪斯
We can't fly the Tardis without him.
他要怎么回来
How's he gonna get back?
你知道它们所有的名字 对吧
You know all their names, don't you?
我在你心里看到的
I saw that in your mind.
每颗星星的名字
The name of every star.
名字有什么意义呢
What's in a name?
名字只是个头衔 不会告诉你任何事情
Names are just titles. Titles don't tell you anything.
就像"博士"
Like "the Doctor"?
就像"蓬帕杜尔夫人"
Like "Madame de Pompadour".
我常希望能靠近一点看那些星星
I have often wished to see those stars a little closer.
就像你那样 我希望
just as you have, I think.
时不时会有
From time to time.
为了救我 你让自己陷入了困境
In saving me, you trapped yourself.
你知道这会发生吗
Did you know that would happen?
非常清楚
Hmm, pretty much.
但你还是来了
Yet still you came.
是的 我来了 不是吗
Yeah, I did, didn't I?
又被抓到做了这种事
Catch me doing that again.
在你我的世界之间还有很多扇门
There were many doors between my world and yours.
你不能用其他的吗
Can you not use one of the others?
当镜子破碎时
When the mirror broke,
冲击会切断与船上的所有连接
the shock would've severed all the links with the ship.
恐怕会有很多的…
There'll be a few more
破碎的镜子和撕破的挂毯出现在各地
broken mirrors and torn tapestries around here I'm afraid,
凡是有时间窗口的地方
wherever there was a time window.
我…我会赔钱的
I'll pay for any damage.
这是个问题 我肯定需要一点钱
That's a thought, I'm gonna need money.
一直以来对钱的概念都很模糊
I've always been a bit vague about money.
你知道哪里可以搞到钱吗
Where do you get money?
所以你就在这里
So here you are.
我孤独的天使
My lonely angel.
和我一起困在了漫长的人生里
Stuck on the slow path with me.
是啊 漫步人生
Yep. The slow path.
敬一杯漫步人生
Here's to the slow path.
真遗憾
It's a pity.
我本应享受漫步人生的
I think I would have enjoyed the slow path.
我哪儿都不去
Well, I'm not going anywhere.
噢 是吗
Oh, aren't you?
握着我的手
Take my hand.
这不是仿制品 就是原来的那个
It's not a copy. It's the original.
我把它搬到这来
I had it moved here
每个细节都精确的还原了
I had it moved here and was exact in every detail.
那个壁炉
The fireplace.
你卧室里的壁炉
The fireplace from your bedroom.
你什么时候做的
When did you do this?
很多年之前
Many years ago.
期盼着…
In the hope
也许某天那扇门可以再次打开
that a door once opened may someday open again.
谁也无法准确知道
One never quite knows
何时会需要自己的博士
when one needs one's doctor.
看起来似乎没有损坏 你认为还能用吗
It appears undamaged. Do you think it will still work?
当你移动的时候 就打破了它与飞船的连接
You broke the bond with the ship when you moved it.
也就是说 镜子破碎之前它就已经离线了
Which means it was off-line when the mirror broke.
所以它没有碎
That's what saved it.
但是
But…
连接基本上是实体的
the link is basically physical
而它的实体还在这儿
and it's still physically here,
也就是说 如果我幸运的话
which might just mean, if I'm lucky,
如果我非常非常非常幸运的话
if I'm very, very, very, very, very lucky…
什么
What?
不稳定连接
Loose connection!
得有人进去修一修
Need to get a man in!
祝我好运
Wish me luck.
不要
No.
蓬帕杜尔夫人
Madame de Pompadour!
还想要看那些星星吗
Still wanna see those stars?
非常想
More than anything.
给我两分钟收拾一下
Give me two minutes. Pack a bag.
我要去哪儿
Am I going somewhere?
去窗口 选一颗星星
Go to the window. Pick a star.
任何星星
Any star.
你们等了多久了
How long did you wait?
五个半小时
Five and half hours.
很好 总是等待五个半小时
Great! Always wait five and half hours.
你去哪儿了
Where‘ve you been?
之后再解释 到塔迪斯里去 一会儿见
Explain later. Into the Tardis. With you in a sec!
瑞娜特
Reinette
你在吗 瑞娜特
Are you there, Reinette?
瑞娜特
Reinette?
噢 你好
Oh, hello.
你刚好错过她了
You just missed her.
她六点到达巴黎
She'll be in Paris by 6:00.
上帝
Good Lord!
她是对的
She was right.
她说你看上去从未变老
She said you never looked a day older.
离我上次见你那么多年了
So many years since I saw you last,
你的脸却一天都没变老
but not a day of it on your face.
她不知谈起过你多少次
She spoke of you many times.
常常盼望着你能再次回来
Often wished you'd visit again.
你知道的 女人嘛
You know how women are.
如今她走了
And there she goes.
最后一次离开凡尔赛
Leaving Versailles for the last time.
她死时只有43岁
Only 43 when she died.
太年轻了
Too young
疾病把她带到了终点
Illness took her in the end.
她总是太努力地工作
She always did work too hard.
她说了什么
What does she say?
当然
Of course.
很对
Quite right.
为什么是她
ROSE: Why her?
为什么它们认为蓬帕杜尔夫人的头
Why did they think they could repair the ship
能够修好它们的船
with the head of Madame de Pompadour?
我们也许永远无法知道了
We'll probably never know.
计算机记忆卡组大规模受损
There's massive damage in the computer memory decks.
也许是搞混了
Probably got confused.
现在维修机器人不在了
The Tardis can close down the time windows
塔迪斯能够关闭时间窗口了
now the droids have gone.
应该不会再搞出什么乱子
Should stop it causing any more trouble.
你没事吧
You all right?
我一直很好
I'm always all right.
来吧 洛斯
Come on, Rose,
你该带我转转塔迪斯的其他地方了
it's time you showed me round the rest of this place.
我亲爱的博士
My dear Doctor,
时间从未过的如此缓慢
the path has never seemed more slow
然而恐怕我快要走到尽头了
and yet I fear I am nearing its end.
理智告诉我 你我不太可能再见面
Reason tells me that you and I are unlikely to meet again,
但我不想听从理智
but I think I shall not listen to reason.
我在你的意识里见过你的世界
I have seen the world inside your head
并知道在那里一切都有可能
and know that all things are possible.
加快脚步好吗 亲爱的
Hurry, though, my love.
现在我的日子越来越短 而我日渐虚弱
My days grow shorter now and I am so very weak.
祝你平安 我孤单的天使
"Godspeed, my lonely angel."
"蓬帕杜尔夫人"号飞船
这里是伦敦
So this is London.
我们世界的一个平行分支
An alternative to our world
这里各种东西都很相似 但又有些许不同
where everything's the same but a little bit different.
我们处在某种不存在的空间
We're in some sort of no place.
大量人口消失于街头
All those people disappearing off the streets,
已经持续好几个月了
it's been going on for months.
它们都在做什么
What are they all doing?
是听筒
It's the earpieces.
模型已经通过了每项测试 先生
MAN: The prototype has passed every test, sir.
可以启动了
It's working.
我见过它们…
I've seen them before.
它们是什么
ROSE: What are they?
金属皮肤
Skin of metal
和不老身躯
and a body that will never age.
是赛博人
Cybus